<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>T. Kurt Bond's µBlog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://consp.org/blog/blog.html"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://consp.org/blog/blog.atom"/>
  <updated>2023-02-14T11:45:04-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>T. Kurt Bond</name>
  </author>
  <id>http://consp.org/blog/blog.atom</id>
  <rights>Copyright © 2023 T. Kurt Bond</rights>
  <generator uri="https://github.com/tkurtbond/microblog/blob/main/Tools/gmi-blog-atom.scm">gmi-blog-atom</generator>

  <entry>
    <title>Almost got to play in an OVA game</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-14-almost-got-to-play-in-an-ova-game.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-14-almost-got-to-play-in-an-ova-game.html</id>
    <updated>2023-02-14T11:45:04-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-02-14 11:45:04-05:00 - Almost got to play in an OVA game&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the BESM 4E game I was playing in came to an unexpected stop, alas.  It looked like it might be replaced with OVA: The Anime Role-Playing Game, but in the end we couldn&amp;#39;t agree on an anime setting to play in, and we ended up playing Deathbringer instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.dyskami.ca/besm.html&quot;&gt;BESM 4E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Eyes%2C_Small_Mouth&quot;&gt;BESM at Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.wiseturtle.com/games.html&quot;&gt;OVA: The Anime Role-Playing Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/396879/Deathbringer-RPG&quot;&gt;Deathbringer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Deathbringer game we played was fun, but I regret not getting to play OVA.  So now I&amp;#39;m rereading OVA and wishing I had the time and a game to play in.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>And now the Atom feeds have the content of the posts in the entries</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-10-and-now-the-atom-feeds-have-the-content-of-the-posts-in-the-entries.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-10-and-now-the-atom-feeds-have-the-content-of-the-posts-in-the-entries.html</id>
    <updated>2023-02-10T13:20:23-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-02-10 13:20:23-05:00 - And now the Atom feeds have the content of the posts in the entries&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way, when you look at an entry in a feed reader, it shows you the content of the blog post, instead of looking empty and requiring you to open the link to the content, however your feed reader does that.  The content has a lot of vertical white space, which seems to be an unfortunate interaction between how I&amp;#39;ve been writing the gemtext of the blog and way the Lichen CMS, which I use to render the gemtext of the blog to HTML, does its conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://lichen.sensorstation.co/&quot;&gt;Lichen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://gemini.circumlunar.space/docs/gemtext.html&quot;&gt;gemtext &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Updated blog and Atom generator to use numeric time zone offsets</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-10-updated-blog-and-atom-generator-to-use-numeric-time-zone-offsets.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-10-updated-blog-and-atom-generator-to-use-numeric-time-zone-offsets.html</id>
    <updated>2023-02-10T08:20:39-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-02-10 08:20:39-05:00 - Updated blog and Atom generator to use numeric time zone offsets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that multiple locations use, colloquially, the same time zone abbreviations for different time zones.  For instance, apparently, EST is used for part of the Americas and also for part of Australia.  So I decided to eliminate that ambiguity and just use the numeric time zone offset in the headers on this blog.  It makes generating the Atom feeds simpler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, that&amp;#39;s right; I&amp;#39;ve updated the blog and sub-blogs to have Atom feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atom_(web_standard)&quot;&gt;Atom Syndication Format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc4287&quot;&gt;RFC 4287 The Atom Syndication Format&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Fuzzy Recollections of a Neat Capability of Unroff: file-insertions</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-07-fuzzy-recollections-of-a-neat-capability-of-unroff.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-07-fuzzy-recollections-of-a-neat-capability-of-unroff.html</id>
    <updated>2023-02-07T15:28:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-02-07 15:28:00-05:00 - Fuzzy Recollections of a Neat Capability of Unroff: file-insertions &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TKB: So, you know how you sometimes need to output something before the data you need to do it has been read from the input?  So normally you save the input data in memory until you’ve read it all, then you find the information you need to output the early bit, then process the input data from memory to produce the output?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CPB: Yep, I have been there before!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TKB: But that is pain if you have to deal with large files and don’t have enough memory.  Usually you’ve got more disk space than memory, so there is an interesting trick you can do instead that I learned from how Unroff (the roff translator written in Elk Scheme) handled cross references and tables of contents when converting to HTML.  You don’t have the section titles for the table of contents or the names of the HTML files they’ll be in (because you’re chucking the output into multiple files) until you have read the whole document.  So, just record the position in the file where the table of contents would go, and has you encounter sections record the section title and the output file it is in and then at the end of generating the files copy the file up to the point where the table of contents is, then output the table of contents with all the correct section titles and links to the output html files, and then copy the rest of the file.  In fact, Unroff generalized to multiple files in such a way that you could record positions to use later in any file and add the necessary information no matter where in the input and output you were.  Very useful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TKB: Back to unroff, I downloaded the source and groffed the manual, and see it is a little more primitive than I remembered.  You used a stream-position function to record the output positions you were interested in, and added the filename, position, and text to be inserted to a list, and at the end of the program you passed all those to the file-insertions procedure (probably as the result of an exit event handler), which did all the rewriting.  This was supported by the streams functionality: “Input, output, and storage of text lines in unroff are centered around a new Scheme data type named stream and a set of primitives that work on streams. A stream can act as a source (input stream) or as a sink (output stream) for lines of text. Streams not only serve as the basis for input and output operations and for the exchange of text with shell commands, but can also be used to temporarily buffer lines of text (e.g. foot- notes or tables of contents) and to implement user-defined macros in a simple way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unroff was written in Elk Scheme, which was a neat early Scheme.  The versions from the original pages are still available, but may not run on modern Unixen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://www-rn.informatik.uni-bremen.de/software/unroff/&quot;&gt;Unroff Home Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://www-rn.informatik.uni-bremen.de/software/unroff/dist/unroff-1.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;Unroff Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://www-rn.informatik.uni-bremen.de/software/elk/&quot;&gt;Elk Scheme: The Extension Language Kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://www-rn.informatik.uni-bremen.de/software/elk/dist.html&quot;&gt;Elk: Distribution and Source Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://www-rn.informatik.uni-bremen.de/software/elk/dist/elk-3.0.tar.gz&quot;&gt;Elk Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a newer version of Elk Scheme that may run on modern Unixen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://sam.zoy.org/elk/&quot;&gt;Elk Scheme - the Extension Language Kit, from Sam Voy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://sam.zoy.org/elk/elk-3.99.8.tar.bz2&quot;&gt;Prerelease: Elk Scheme 3.99.8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the manuals that come with Unroff in PDF:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://consp.org/files/unroff/unroff.1.pdf&quot;&gt;unroff.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://consp.org/files/unroff/unroff-html-man.1.pdf&quot;&gt;unroff-html-man.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://consp.org/files/unroff/manual.ms.pdf&quot;&gt;manual.ms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://consp.org/files/unroff/unroff-html.1.pdf&quot;&gt;unroff-html.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http://consp.org/files/unroff/unroff-html-ms.1.pdf&quot;&gt;unroff-html-ms.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Dynamic Powers vs. Power Flux in BESM 4E</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-07-dynamic-powers-vs.power-flux-in-besm-4e.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-07-dynamic-powers-vs.power-flux-in-besm-4e.html</id>
    <updated>2023-02-07T10:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-02-07 10:20:00-05:00 - Dynamic Powers vs. Power Flux in BESM 4E&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m rereading this section in BESM 4E (pages 259–260) and think it is pretty good advice for using Dynamic Powers, Power Flux, and Power Variation.  I found the Dynamic Sorcery difficult to get my mind around in BESM 2E, and as far as I can tell there wasn&amp;#39;t equivalent advice in BESM 3E, although I think its versions of Dynamic Powers, Power Flux, and Power Variation are very similiar to those in BESM 4E.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is also in Tri-Stat Core RPG (pages 157–158), as well.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>How I Edit This Blog</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-06-How-I-Edit-This-Blog.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-06-How-I-Edit-This-Blog.html</id>
    <updated>2023-02-06T22:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-02-06 22:16:00-05:00 - How I Edit This Blog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use GNU Emacs, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/&quot;&gt;GNU Emacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The file tkb-microblog.el contains everything I wrote to support editing these blog posts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tkurtbond/emacs-lisp/blob/master/tkb-microblog.el&quot;&gt;tkb-microblog.el &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I execute the tkb-microblog function it prompts me for the blog post title, then asks what sub-blogs I want to add it to, if any.  Then it adds a link to the new blog post file to the main blog index and each of the sub-blog indexes I specified, creating them if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function tkb-find-file-hook makes sure that I edit gemtext files (which end in .gmi) with visual-line-mode on and auto-fill-mode off, because gemini browsers wraps long lines, unless they are preformatted text, and paragraphs are indicated by blank lines.  I also have a minor mode that rebinds M-q (which is normally bound to fill-paragraph) to a function that tells the user not to do that, because the lines are not supposed to be filled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I think it works well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amusingly, right now tkb-microblog.el is 131 lines, about 26% the size of the Lichen CMS, at 494 lines, that I use to render the gemtext of this blog to HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://lichen.sensorstation.co/&quot;&gt;Lichen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 7</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-05-Mini-Six-Middle-Sea-Game-session-7.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-05-Mini-Six-Middle-Sea-Game-session-7.html</id>
    <updated>2023-02-05T23:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-02-05 14:19:00-05:00 - Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 7&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;http://consp.org/blog/2023/ambush-at-the-maple-tree-the-end.png&quot; alt=&quot;The End of the Ambush at the Maple Tree&quot;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the combat {at the last session} there are 5 Sanguine Sons who are incapacitated and 3 that are paralyzed.  The PCs tie them all up and decide to interrogate them.  Ruan realizes doing it separately and out of the other Sons&amp;#39; sight and hearing will let the PCs confirm the individual stories against each other.  Ruan and Treave take the Sons, one at a time, around the tree and interrogate them.  The start with a Son who turns out to be the second in command of this ambush.  (The leader was dead.)  Initially resistant, after Ruan cuts off his finger he quickly capitulates and answers their questions.  The Sons think that the prophecy is false and the PCs interest in it is because they are working against the Sons, hence the ambush.  The Sons&amp;#39; aim is to gain enough power from possession of an artifact (perhaps the Eye of Zetha?) to take over Korianthor and take their proper place at the top.  The Son thinks that their leader Nikos Pamboridis gets some of his intel from someone that the Sons don&amp;#39;t know about.  Ruan gives the severed finger back to its owner, as if he is mocking or emphasizing its loss, which terrifies the Son more than anything else.  The other Sons basically confirm all this, and reveal their horses are picketed about 500 yards away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PCs decide to kill all the Sons and disappear their bodies and their dogs.  Bersaba flies up out of the maple forest, where she sees that the maple holding Saphira&amp;#39;s temple is over 3000 feet tall and its branches spread over 1500 feet wide!  She flies around looking for a lake they can dump the bodies in and finds one, where a rocky valley was blocked by a landslide and filled with water.  When she returns Locryn uses the Beast Tongue spell to promise the horses freedom and food if they overcome their natural dislike of the smell of blood and carry the bodies of the Sons and their dogs to the lake.  The horses agree.  The PCs load the bodies and head off for the lake, about 4 hours away, leading the horses.  On the way they pass through a valley with good grazing and the horses say this would be a fine place to eat after their chore is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon reaching the lake the rest of the PCs are surprised and a little worried when they find out Morwen knows all the best tricks for disposing of bodies in lakes — slash the bellies and stuff them full of rocks — as if she has done this before!  They release the horses before starting the bloody work, and the horses immediately head back over the trail to their grazing.  They keep some crossbows and all the remaining bolts, pry the gems out of the hilts of a number of the swords, and toss the bodies, still wearing their armor, the swords, and the horses tack into the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was dark now, so they made camp for the night away from their body dump and washed off the signs of their grisly deeds.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>BESM 4E's Dimension Walk Attribute is exactly Shadow Shifting from Zelazny's Amber Chronicles</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-01.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-02-01.html</id>
    <updated>2023-02-01T12:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-02-01 12:00:00-05:00 - BESM 4E&amp;#39;s Dimension Walk Attribute is EXACTLY Shadow Shifting from Zelazny&amp;#39;s Amber Chronicles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big Eyes, Small Mouth 4E&amp;#39;s Dimension Walk Attribute is EXACTLY Shadow Shifting from Zelazny&amp;#39;s Amber Chronicles!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read the Dimension Walk attribute description a character concept came into my head and I HAD to write it down!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, looking back I see it first showed up in BESM 3E.  Still, neat!&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>If you get the message "Error: unbound variable: geiser#geiser-eval" when working with CHICKEN Scheme and geiser...</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-30.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-30.html</id>
    <updated>2023-01-30T13:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-01-30 13:39:00-05:00 - If you get the message &amp;quot;Error: unbound variable: geiser#geiser-eval&amp;quot; when working with CHICKEN Scheme and geiser...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... it means you need to go back and follow the instructions for CHICKEN support, and also update your geiser packages in emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://wiki.call-cc.org/emacs#geiser&quot;&gt;Using geiser with CHICKEN Scheme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 6</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-29.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-29.html</id>
    <updated>2023-01-29T23:06:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-01-29 23:06:00-05:00 - Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 6&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was mostly finishing a combat from the last session, since we spent time beforehand spending character points and updating characters.  The PCs murdered many of a group of various second and succeeding sons of various noble houses who ambushed them because the PCs oppose their evil plan to take over, and killed their HUGE, VICIOUS DOGS TOO...  Next session they plan to interrogate the survivors.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Owlbear Rodeo 1.0 will be open-sourced</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-29a.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-29a.html</id>
    <updated>2023-01-29T14:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-01-29 14:42:00-05:00 - Owlbear Rodeo 1.0 will be open-sourced&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is old news, but according to the Owlbear.Rodeo folks, Owlbear.Rodeo 1.0 will eventually be shut down, but it will also be open-sourced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve found Owlbear.Rodeo to be an excellent simple virtual table top (VTT), easy to use and low overhead.  Combined with Discord for audio and dice rolling it&amp;#39;s a great way to play any RPG that doesn&amp;#39;t have a dedicated VTT implementation.  I put the character sheets and campaign notes in Google Drive, and sometimes use a Google Sheets spreadsheet for games with per-character initiative, like the one I use for Mini Six.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://blog.owlbear.rodeo/owlbear-rodeo-2-0-timeline-update/&quot;&gt;Road to Owlbear Rodeo 2.0 - Timeline Updates and Owlbear Rodeo 1.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_tabletop_game#Virtual_tabletops&quot;&gt;Virtual Table Top (VTT)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1rJwv0YSkGGTUc1WGUj_CvdeKYZ9W92_MPz-brMKR4AM/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;Mini Six Initiative Tracker Template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://tkurtbond.github.io/posts/2020/11/29/looking-at-the-mini-six-rpg-and-related-games/&quot;&gt;Mini Six&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 5</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-22.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-22.html</id>
    <updated>2023-01-22T15:34:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-01-22 15:34:00-05:00 - Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIMEWARP: This entry brought to you by the power of TIME TRAVEL!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was another online game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifteen misty green female figures materialize from the surface of the pool on the lower level and wail!  Locryn runs away.  Iria, made of sterner stuff, tries to stay and explain the PCs mean no harm, but one of the figures floats over to her and attacks her psychically, almost incapacitating her!  She runs away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While waiting for Iria to recover one of the characters mentions that they had noticed that one of the ghostly green figures was wearing an amulet.  Thinking of the medallions they had discovered earlier they put them on and go back downstairs.  The misty figures do not appear, and they continue exploring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Ruan and Bersaba accidently set a table in an alchemy lab on fire and are badly burned they discover the pool on this level is also full of healing water.  They interact with several items which give them various feelings.  They find a staff carved as if it was a woman stretched disturbingly thin, which gave them feelings of dread.  Iria foolishly put the staff in the pool, which resulted in an explosion, and clouds of steam!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They find another secret door, leading to a steep stair going down into a room with a carving of Saphira on the north wall and an altar.  They chant the ritual and summon the oracle and the carving of Saphira comes to life, and after convincing her that their aims were true, she reveals they can find the Hammer of Torgoth in the tomb of the Sorcerer-Smith Torgoth, located on Mount Wasarey in the Presaris Mountains, about a week&amp;#39;s travel west from Korianthor, and says “Only the hammer of Torgoth can silence the Eye of Zetha.  Beware the touch of the eye, since the evil is greater since the passing of Alekos Vasiliou.”  Each of the characters is gifted with two small gourds with stoppers, and told “These will help you when you are wounded.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they leave the temple, they are ambushed by well armed and dressed men and a pack of huge, fierce mastiff, also wearing armor!  These must be some of the Sanguine Sons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;http://consp.org/blog/2023/sanguine-sons-ambush.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ambush!&quot;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PCs are stuck in the entryway of the temple, menaced by mastiffs close at hand, while the Sanguine Sons attack with crossbows from a distance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;http://consp.org/blog/2023/dogs-attack.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dogs Attack!&quot;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 4</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-15.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-15.html</id>
    <updated>2023-01-15T16:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-01-15 23:03-05:00 - Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 4&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to run another session today of the Middle Sea Mini Six game I&amp;#39;ve been running for the kids, the fourth session, online.  They&amp;#39;ve been taking an in-depth approach, so it&amp;#39;s taking more time that I anticipated, in an enjoyable way.  They travelled to the Votlem Range seeking the abandoned temple of Saphira, getting directions in a remote village.  Along the way they see an albino stag and end up fighting the wolves that were following it.  The next day they see the stag again, and it leads them more directly to the temple than their previous instructions would have taken them.   The temple is in a maple tree that is over 100 feet in diameter!  They figure out how to open the temple doors and explored it, finding a pool of healing water, a mysterious bumble bee, a room with remains of ritual robes and some silver medallions, secret passages, a throne with a secret compartment containing a book telling how to invoke the oracle, and a stairway to a deeper level, where they started to explore further but all but Locryn and Iria were driven back to the upper level by frightening misty green apparitions of women.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>A Banner Image</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-10.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-10.html</id>
    <updated>2023-01-10T10:40:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-01-10 10:40:00-05:00 - A Banner Image&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend thought I should put a image on my micro site/blog, so I did.  It is at the index page for the site, and in this post as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; src=&quot;http://consp.org/microblog-banner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;../../microblog-banner.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>BESM Multiverse: Anime RPG World Expansions</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-07.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-07.html</id>
    <updated>2023-01-07T12:58:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-01-07 12:58:00-05:00 - BESM Multiverse: Anime RPG World Expansions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just finished my Backerkit survey for this kickstarter, and I&amp;#39;m looking forward to getting it.  I&amp;#39;m interested in more detail about BESM&amp;#39;s multiverse, and I&amp;#39;m especially looking forward to the new edition of BESM Uresia.  And I just picked up another copy of the rules and Dramatis Personae in print.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/dyskami/besm-multiverse-anime-rpg-world-expansions&quot;&gt;BESM Multiverse: Anime RPG World Expansions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>The New Year is Here!</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-01.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2023/2023-01-01.html</id>
    <updated>2023-01-01T01:01:01-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2023-01-01 00:01:00-05:00 - The New Year is Here!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve been investigating (and terrifying) smugglers, racing dinosaurs, and engaging in gladitorial combat (though not to the death)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;14:23-05:00 - Cults, Undead, and Ziggurats in Old Port Nyanzaru&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After competing in the Arena, we continued looking for fragments of the artificat, being approached to deal with a cult of deranged Grungs, rescue a rescue party trying to retrieve kidnapped citizens, and in the process murdering cultists, sending undead to their final rest, and finding a person of evil magic intent on feeding their undead on us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;23:12-05:00 - Books Read in 2022&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read 568 books in 2022.  My books read per day average was about 1.556.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Spending New Year's Eve the Right Way!</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2022/2022-12-31.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2022/2022-12-31.html</id>
    <updated>2022-12-31T23:01:01-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2022-12-31 23:45:00-05:00 - Spending New Year&amp;#39;s Eve the Right Way!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m spending New Year&amp;#39;s Eve playing D&amp;amp;D online with my regular Saturday group, the best way to spend the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I&amp;#39;ve made the git repo I used to host this micro site and micro blog public, for no particular reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tkurtbond/microblog&quot;&gt;https://github.com/tkurtbond/microblog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>New (micro) blog!</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2022/2022-12-30.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2022/2022-12-30.html</id>
    <updated>2022-12-30T23:01:01-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2022-12-30 20:22:00-05:00 - New (micro) blog!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran across Lichen, a Content Management System written in Forth and which uses Gemtext (which reminded me of Gemini; something to look at again).  Anyway, I decided to try out Lichen, which can statically render Gemtext to HTML, thinking its light cognitive overhead might encourage me to blog more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://lichen.sensorstation.co/&quot;&gt;Lichen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://gemini.circumlunar.space/&quot;&gt;Gemini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;gemini://gemini.circumlunar.space/&quot;&gt;... in Geminispace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://gemini.circumlunar.space/docs/gemtext.html&quot;&gt;Gemtext&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;gemini://gemini.circumlunar.space/docs/gemtext.html&quot;&gt;... in Geminispace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose it would be simpler if I just used Gemini, but then I&amp;#39;d have to figure out somewhere to host it, or run a server myself...  &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 3</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2022/2022-12-23.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2022/2022-12-23.html</id>
    <updated>2022-12-23T13:50:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2022-12-23 13:50:00-05:00 - Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIMEWARP: This entry brought to you by the power of TIME TRAVEL!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a hiatus of 1 year and 195 days I got to run another session of the Mini Six Middle Sea game I&amp;#39;m running for the “kids”, face to face!  (They&amp;#39;re all grown, but I still call them that.)  Anyway, this time they continued following up information about the prophecy by being introduced by Maeloc to Nessa Vivyan, who looks at the scroll and tells them the it prophesies that the Eye of Zetha, a relic of the ancient malevolent goddess Zetha, will once again lead the land into darkness, unless someone uses the Hammer of Torgoth to defeat the Eye of Zetha, and says that the references to an oracle that rests beneath the boughs of of a maple tree probably refers to the temple of Saphira, an ancient goddess of harvest and growth, whose long abandoned temple is in a huge maple tree in a valley in the dangerous Votlem Range a week&amp;#39;s travel south east of Korianthor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then they investigating the Sanguine Sons and their leader Nikos Pamboridis and their involvement in the prophecy.  They surveil Nikos&amp;#39;s house, and discover that while normal visitors come to the front door a bunch of very unsavory, criminal looking, folks come to the back door.  Investigating leads them to the headquarters of what turns out to be the headquarters of a criminal gang, the Ravens, who have been gaining influence.  In the process of figuring this out they trade their promise to Cyprien Glafcou, the leader of another gang, to help that gang break into a hard target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On their way back to their lodgings they are ambushed by thugs, and murder them all easily. &lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 2</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2021/2021-06-11.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2021/2021-06-11.html</id>
    <updated>2021-06-11T16:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2021-06-11 16:23:00-05:00 - Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day they split up to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anaoc, Brannok, Morwen, and Treave went to the First Pepper, to listen to the political discussion.  Anaoc noticed some people seem to be conspiring, more than one group.  Treave talked to several people and figures out there are at least four different known conspiracies, with one of them a conspiracy of a demagogue, a bunch of nobles, and surprising, perhaps a criminal gang.  Anaoc used ESP on someone (Vaso Anastillis) and found out the Sanguine Sons are group of young, discontent, second-son or succeeding (only the first born inherits) noble scion who are supporting unpleasant political figures and are intimidating, beating, and murdering their opponents.  Nikos Pamboridis is a noble, and Vaso thinks of someone he knew who was  beaten to death when the PCs asked about him, but only said he lives by himself in small but impressive house near the house of his family, which is lead by Fotis Pamboridis.  Treave asked about the blood symbol and Vaso said there is a group murdering people and leaving three stylized blood drops on a scrap of parchment on the bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryd, Locryn, Greeth, and Bersaba went to the forum to find out about the scroll and Nessa.  Locryn found a scholar, Maeloc Minear, who is knowledgeable about languages, and treated him to drinks at the Friendly Owl, a scholar&amp;#39;s bar (tea &amp;amp; herbal infusions).  He told the PCs a little about the scroll, and turned out to have a friend Nessa Vivyan (**!**) who could tell them more.  The PCs speculated that this is the Nessa of the note, and told Maeloc of the assassin and suggested that Nessa may also be in danger.  Maeloc decided to accompany them to visit Nessa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is mid-afternoon.  The PCs are split up, and haven&amp;#39;t gone anywhere yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s where it ended.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

  <entry>
    <title>Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 1</title>
    <link href="http://consp.org/blog/2021/2021-06-04.html"/>
    <id>http://consp.org/blog/2021/2021-06-04.html</id>
    <updated>2021-06-04T16:15:00-05:00</updated>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;main&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;2021-06-04 16:15:00-05:00 - Mini Six Middle Sea Game, session 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIMEWARP: This entry brought to you by the power of TIME TRAVEL!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PCs stayed at a coaching in on the way to Korianthor, the Jewel of the Southern Continent. The PCs woke in the middle of the night to screaming and found another patron just being killed by an assassin. The PCs captured the assassin and Anaoc Rosewarne interrogated him using ESP.  He turned out to be Mairi Vitalelli, sent by a wealthy noble with a smirk, associated in his mind somehow with three blood drops, and seeking a scroll case.  Searching him they found a note signed NP (probably Nikos Pamboridis; see ESP!) with three stylized blood drops telling him where and when and who.  The PCs searched, and found the scroll cached above a loose board in the ceiling.  The scroll was covered in glyphs that nobody can read, but the scroll case has a note as well — “My dear fellow, can you have found it at last?  Bring it to me in Korianthor and we will see if there is any way to escape the prophecy! — Nessa”.  There is a quick trial and Mairi was hung with a short drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They arrived in Korianthor during the Festival of Masks (like Mardi Gras or Carnival in Venice), when plain masks are worn during the day and elaborite masks are worn at night.  Everybody bought two masks.  They found lodging at The Green Dragon, then went to the forum to enjoy the Festival, observed a gang of thieves at work there.  Ryd approached the leader of the gang, Cyprien Glafcou, and impressed him and found out Nikos Pamboridis was of a “political persuasion” and gave the name of the tavern which he said attracted like souls.  In the forum they met Treave Carwithin, Bersaba Kitto, Morwen Polglaze, and Locryn Treglown, and suggested they also stay at the Green Dragon.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/main&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>

</feed>
